Manfred F. DeMartino Collection of CBS Radio Scripts
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
Manfred F. DeMartino Collection of CBS Radio Scripts 1943-1945
De Martino, Manfred F.
.42 linear feet (1 box)
Recorded Sound Reference Center, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Scripts and a photograph acquired by Manfred F. DeMartino while working backstage at CBS radio during the mid-1940s. Includes scripts for the Frank Sinatra Show, Philip Morris Playhouse, and Your Hit Parade.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
DeMartino, Manfred F.; Fontaine, Joan, 1917- --Autographs.; Kelton, Pert--Autographs.; Roventini, Johnny--Autographs.; Roventini, Johnny--Photographs.; Sinatra, Frank, 1915-1998--Autographs.; Todd, Dick--Autographs.; Tone, Franchot--Autographs.
Organizations
Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.
Subjects
Popular music--United States--1941-1950.; Radio advertising--United States.; Radio programs, Musical.
Titles
Frank Sinatra show (Radio program); Philip Morris playhouse (Radio program); Your hit parade (Radio program)
Form/Genre
Radio scripts.
Administrative Information
Collection Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Manfred F. DeMartino, 2004.
Additions
No further additions to the collection are expected.
Access Restrictions
The Manfred F. DeMartino Collection of CBS Radio Scripts is open for research.
Biographical Note
Prof. Manfred F. DeMartino, who studied and authored books on human sexuality, worked on the CBS backstage crew in the mid-1940s, while he was a student at Brooklyn College.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of scripts and a photograph acquired by Manfred Frank DeMartino while working backstage at CBS radio during the mid-1940s. Includes scripts for the Frank Sinatra Show, Philip Morris Playhouse, and Your Hit Parade, many of which are autographed by performers. The scripts include advertisements for sponsors such as Vimms Vitamins, Philip Morris cigarettes, and the American Tobacco Company's Lucky Strike cigarettes. The black and white photograph of Philip Morris spokesman Johnny Roventini is autographed.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
Series 1: Photograph, undated
Series 2: Scripts, 1943-1945
http://lccn.loc.gov/2004654583
Container List
- Series 1. Photograph, undated, 1 folder
  - Autographed photograph of Philip Morris spokesman Johnny Roventini, undated (Folder 1)
- Series 2. Scripts, 1943-1945, 8 folders
  - Script for the Frank Sinatra Show, 1944 April 26 (Folder 2)
    Autographed by Pert Kelton.
  - Script for the Frank Sinatra Show, 1944 December 4 (Folder 3)
  - Philip Morris Playhouse script for "Magnificent Obsession," 1944 January 27 (Folder 4)
    Autographed by Joan Fontaine.
  - Philip Morris Playhouse script for "Here Comes Mr. Jordan," 1944 February 11 (Folder 5)
    Autographed by Franchot Tone.
  - Philip Morris Playhouse script for "The Lodger," 1944 February 18 (Folder 6)
  - Your Hit Parade script, 1943 October 16 (Folder 7)
    Autographed by Frank Sinatra.
  - Your Hit Parade script, 1944 April 8 (Folder 8)
    Autographed by Harry Altman.
  - Your Hit Parade script, 1945 August 25 (Folder 9)
    Autographed by Dick Todd.